Finding Aid for Willow Run Public School Library records, 1944-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Willow Run Public School Library records
1944-1969
Willow Run Public School Library.
86304 Bz 2; BZ Outsize
Files collected by Nell Barrett, head librarian, Willow Run Public School Library concerning history of Willow Run, Michigan, and activities of the schools and library system.
4 linear feet
3 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Nell Barrett (donor no. 4948 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Nell Barrett was head librarian at the Willow Run Public School Library. In addition, she was a collector of material relating to the history of the Willow Run community.
The collection consists of materials collected by Nell Barrett, head librarian at the Willow Run Public School Library relating to Willow Run. Included are materials relating to her work as a librarian, background information, scrapbooks and clippings, and photographs.
Subjects:
Libraries--Michigan--Willow Run.; Schools--Michigan--Willow Run.; Washtenaw Area Library Association (Mich.); Willow Run (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Art education.; Buildings--Michigan--Willow Run.; Children--1941-1950.; Children drawing and painting.; Children playing.; Classrooms--Michigan--Willow Run.; Dwellings--Michigan--Willow Run.; Education.; Fires--Michigan--Willow Run.; Interiors.; Libraries--Michigan--Willow Run.; Schools--Michigan--Willow Run.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Buildings.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Fires.; Willow Run (Mich.)--Schools.; Willow Run Public School Library.; Willow Run Community Schools (Willow Run, Mich.)
Contributors:
Barrett, Nell.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Materials collected by Nell Barrett, head librarian, Willow Run Public School Library
  - Willow Run Public School Library (Box 1)
  - Washtenaw Area Library Association (Box 2)
  - Scrapbooks relating to Willow Run, 1942-1944; 3 volumes
    - Scrapbooks relating to Willow Run, 1942-1944 (Volume 1)
    - Scrapbooks relating to Willow Run, 1942-1944 (Volume 2)
      (continued)
    - Scrapbooks relating to Willow Run, 1942-1944 (Volume 3)
  - Scrapbooks and clippings re. Willow Run, 1940s-1950s (Box 3)
  - Ypsilanti Township news clippings, 1961-1964 (Box 4)
  - Willow Run Association for Neighborhood Development (WRAND) newsletter (Box 4)
  - Paper by John McConnell, "The Ypsilanti Township Republican Party", 1963 (Box 4)
  - "The Willow Run Story" by Marion F. Wilson (Box 4)
    (edited manuscript)
  - Miscellaneous concerning history of Willow Run (Box 4)
  - Photographs
    The Photographs includes prints of buildings and school activities of the Willow Run (Mich.) Public Schools; also photos of Willow Run housing during and after World War II.
    - Buildings-Other than schools and housing (Box 4)
    - Housing
      - Fires (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous activities (Box 4)
    - Library (Box 4)
    - Schools
      - Classroom scenes-Art (Box 4)
      - Classroom scenes-General (Box 4)
      - Exteriors, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous activities-Adults (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous activities-Children (Box 4)
      - Staff and administration (Box 4)